Finding Aid for the Smith, Thomas Lynn Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Smith, Thomas Lynn Collection
1934-1948
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0402
.42 linear_feet
Scope and Contents
The collection contains journal articles, in pamphlet form, written by Thomas Lynn Smith, a Sociology Professor. The topics range from studies of Southern Culture to social structures in the countries of Brazil, Colombia, and El Salvador..
- Pamphlets
  - ‘An Analysis of Rural Social Organization Among the French-Speaking People of Southern Louisiana’ Reprinted from Journal of Farm Economics, October, 1934
  - ‘An Analysis of the Changes in Social Organization of the American Agricultural Village from 1900 to 1930’ Reprinted from University of Minnesota, Summaries of Ph.D. Theses, 1939
  - ‘Brazilian Land Surveys, Land Division, and Land Titles’ Reprinted from Rural Sociology, September, 1944
  - ‘Characteristics of Migrants’ Reprinted from The Southwestern Social Science Quarterly, March, 1941
  - ‘Colonization and Settlement in Colombia’ Reprinted from Rural Sociology, June, 1947
  - ‘The Country Butchery: A Co-Operative Institution’ Reprinted from Rural Sociology, September, 1937
  - ‘The Cultural Setting of Agricultural Extension Work in Colombia’ Reprinted from Rural Sociology, September, 1945
  - ‘The Demographic Basis of Old Age Assistance in the South’ Reprinted from Social Forces, March, 1939
  - ‘The Demographic Study of the American Negro’ Reprinted from Social Forces, September, 1945
  - ‘The Educational Status of Louisiana’s Farm Population’ Reprinted from Louisiana Bulletin, December, 1947
  - ‘The Growth and Distribution of Population in Brazil’ Reprinted from The Proceedings of the Louisiana Academy of Sciences, December, 1944
  - ‘The Locality Group Structure of Brazil’ Reprinted from American Sociological Review, February 1944
  - ‘Migracion Seleccionada’ Reprinted from Tierras y Aguas, July, 1944
  - ‘Needed Emphases in Southern Sociology’ Reprinted from Social Forces, December, 1948
  - ‘Notes on Population and Social Organization in the Central Portion of the Sao Francisco Valley’ Reprinted from Inter-American Economic Affairs, December, 1947
  - ‘Notes on Population and Rural Social Organization in El Salvador’ Reprinted from Rural Sociology, December, 1945
  - ‘Population Redistribution in Louisiana’ Reprinted from Social Forces, May, 1942
  - ‘Recent Changes in the Farm Population of the Southern States’ Reprinted from Social Forces, March, 1937
  - ‘The Significance of Reported Trends in Louisiana Agriculture’ Reprinted from Southwestern Social Science Quarterly, December, 1941
  - ‘The Social Effects of Land Division in Relationship to a Program of Land Utilization’ Reprinted from Journal of Farm Economics, November, 1935
  - ‘Sources and Distribution of the Farm Population in Relation to Farm Benefit Payments’ Reprinted from Journal of Farm Economics, August, 1941
  - ‘Village Growth and Decline, 1930-40’ Reprinted from Rural Sociology, June, 1944